That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
（ミリム）
マブダチの子分に何するのだ〜！
What do you think you're doing
to my bestie's subordinate?!
Episode 18: Evil Creeps Closer
Damn it! She'll pay for that!
クソ！　許せねえ
俺を誰だと思ってる…
黒豹牙(こくひょうが)フォビオだぞ
Who does she think I am?
I'm Phobio the Black Leopard Fang!
（エンリオ）
魔王ミリムが相手では
不可抗力というものです
With the Demon Lord Milim in the
picture, it's beyond our control.
たとえ 魔王カリオン様でも…
Even for the Demon Lord Carrion.
バカ野郎！
You idiot!
Lord Carrion wouldn't have
humiliated himself like this!
カリオン様なら こんな無様(ぶざま)は
さらさなかっただろうぜ
俺が未熟だっただけの話よ
I just wasn't good enough.
But my pride won't allow
me to go back empty-handed.
しかし このまま成果なく戻るのは
俺の誇りが許さんのだ
あいつらは 自分たちで
町を作っていやがったな
Those guys built a town all on their own.
I saw them as no more than lowly monsters,
下等な魔物だと侮っていたが
俺たちでも及ばぬような技術を
持っていやがる
but they have skills and
techniques that even we lack.
全くです
That's for sure.
配下に加えるなどと言わず
Instead of ordering them to serve us,
我らがユーラザニアと
国交を結びたいほどですな
I'd like to see Eurazania establish
diplomatic relations with them.
Yeah. Even if the Demon Lord
Milim hadn't been involved,
魔王ミリムがいなかったとしても
俺の対応は間違っていた
I handled that all wrong.
I couldn't have gained their trust by just
taking over without giving them a say.
頭ごなしに支配しても
ヤツらの信頼は
得られなかっただろうからな
But it's too late now.
だが 今更だぜ
My wounds may heal, but this
humiliation will never fade.
この屈辱は
ケガが癒えても消えやしねえ
カリオン様に迷惑をかけねえように
I want to take revenge somehow,
so I won't cause trouble for Lord Carrion.
なんとかして
復讐(ふくしゅう)してやりたいんだよ
そうは申されましても
復讐など 現実的では…
That's easy to say, but
revenge isn't realistic...
分かってんだよ！
頭では無理だって
I know that! I know in my
head that it won't work!
だけど こればっかりは
理屈じゃねえんだよ！
Still, I just can't rationalize this!
（フットマン）
ホ〜ホッホッホッホ！
Who's there?!
何者だ！
Oh, how well I understand that
vexation you must be feeling!
（フットマン）
いやいや〜 その悔しい気持ち
この私にも
よ〜く理解できますねえ
Greetings, fine people!
ごきげんよう 皆様
私はフットマンと申します
My name is Footman.
フットマン？
Footman?
I am a member of the
Moderate Harlequin Alliance,
（フットマン）中庸道化連(ちゅうようどうけれん)が一人
the one they call Footman the Angry Pierrot!
“アングリーピエロ”の
フットマンとは 私のこと
Pleasure to make your acquaintance!
どうぞ お見知りおきを
Now, please don't be so guarded.
（ティア）
そんなに警戒しないでほしいな！
I'm Tear, and I'm not your enemy!
あたいはティア！
あなたたちの敵じゃないよ
What do you want?
何の用だ？
（フットマン）ホ〜ホッホ！
Well, I was summoned here
by your anger and hatred.
私はね
怒りと憎しみの感情に呼ばれて
やって来たのですよ
Anger and hatred?
（フォビオ）怒りと憎しみ？
I sensed some choice waves of anger, you see.
（フットマン）
上質な怒りの波動を感じました
Please tell me what has angered you so.
（フットマン）
何を お怒りになっているのか
ぜひとも お聞かせください
I'm certain I can be of some help to you.
きっと
力になってご覧に入れますから…
フォビオ様 このような者どもの
話を聞く必要はございません
Sir Phobio, there is no need
to listen to these people.
排除してもよろしいですか？
May I remove them from your presence?
We are the Beast King's Beastketeers,
serving the Demon Lord Carrion.
我々は 魔王カリオンの
獣王戦士団(じゅうおうせんしだん)に属する者
Do you honestly think you wandering
majin are any match for us?
野良の魔人程度が
相手になるとでも思ったか？
You desire power, do you not?
（フットマン）
力が欲しいのでしょう？
We have it... power akin
to none you've ever seen.
ございますよ
とびっきりの力が
Naturally, however, it comes with great risk.
当然ですが 危険も大きい
But should you triumph over that risk,
しかし その危険に打ち勝ったとき
得られる力は絶大です
the power you stand to gain is immense.
ほう？
Oh?
フォビオ様！
Sir Phobio!
You want to defeat the
Demon Lord Milim, right?
（ティア）
勝ちたいんだよね？　魔王ミリムに
Then you just need to become
a Demon Lord yourself!
だったらさ
あんたも魔王になっちゃいなよ！
ま… おう
Demon... Lord?!
A Demon Lord? You think you can
fool me with nonsense like that?
（フォビオ）魔王だと？
そのような戯言(ざれごと)で
俺を だませるなどと…
Charybdis.
（フットマン）カリュブディス…
（フォビオ）ハッ！
Have you heard of it?
（フットマン）
ご存じありませんか？
カリュブディス… だと？
Did you say... Charybdis?
Yeah, if you had the evil power
of that gigantic beast-fish,
（ティア）あ〜あ
あの大怪魚の邪悪な力なら
魔王に匹敵するんだけどな〜
you'd be a Demon Lord's equal...
But if you don't want it,
we'll just go find someone who does!
いらないんなら ほかを当たるから
もう行くね
Come on, let's go!
ほら！　行こ
（フットマン）
ホッホッホ 残念ですねえ
What a shame.
（フォビオ）待て！
Wait!
なりません フォビオ様！
Sir Phobio, you mustn't!
I haven't liked any of this from the start.
（フォビオ）
俺は最初から 面白くなかったんだ
Why was a useless Orc Lord
chosen to be a Demon Lord?
なんでオークロードのような雑魚が
魔王に抜擢(ばってき)されるんだ
That's bull!
ふざけるな！
If they need a new Demon Lord, I'll...
新しい魔王が必要だと
いうなら 俺が…
I'll get stronger! Then even Lord
Carrion will forgive me with a smile!
俺が強くなるなら
カリオン様だって
笑って許してくれるだろうぜ
Sir Phobio...
（エンリオ）フォビオ様…
（フォビオ）詳しく聞かせろ
Tell me more!
Ah! I knew the great
Sir Phobio would understand!
（フットマン）
おお！
さすがにフォビオ様ですねえ
Yes, of course! There is none more
suited than you to be a Demon Lord!
そうでしょうとも
魔王となるのは あなたをおいて
ほかには いませんとも！
（ティア）
やっぱり 強い者が
魔王にならないと間違ってるよね
It's just wrong for anyone who isn't
strong to be a Demon Lord, right?!
That's how I feel, too!
あたいも そう思うよ
And as far as that goes,
you're perfect for the job!
その点
フォビオ様なら適任だよね！
What do you two stand to gain from this deal?
（フォビオ）
この話 てめえらに何の得がある？
What are you after?
目的は何だ？
We just want you to give us special
treatment once you become a Demon Lord!
（ティア）
魔王になったら あたいたちを
贔屓(ひいき)にしてくれたらいい
We'd like you to do a few favors for us, too!
当然 いろいろと
便宜を図ってもらいたいしね
（フットマン）ホッホッホ
We cannot subdue Charybdis
on our own, after all.
我々だけでは カリュブディスを
従えることはできませんからねえ
We managed to find the place
where it's been sealed away,
（ティア）
せ〜っかく
封印された場所を見つけたけど
but as it is now, we're just
sitting on a gold mine!
このままじゃ 宝の持ち腐れだし
And we just happened to find
you at the perfect time!
（フットマン）
タイミング良く
フォビオ様を お見かけしましてね
なるほどな
I see.
But there's no telling whether
I can subdue Charybdis or not...
だが 俺が カリュブディスを
従えることができるかどうかは…
（フットマン）ホ〜ホッホ！
If anyone can do it,
it's you, great Sir Phobio!
フォビオ様なら
必ずや成功するでしょう
You'll be fine!
（ティア）大丈夫 大丈夫！
So when I become a Demon Lord,
（フォビオ）
俺が魔王になったときに
they want to be the ones credited
for helping me the most?
自分たちが最も役に立ったって
実績が欲しいってことか
その話 引き受けようじゃねえか
All right, I accept your offer.
You three can go back.
（フォビオ）お前たちは戻れ
（エンリオ）フォビオ様！
Sir Phobio!
（フォビオ）事の顛末(てんまつ)を伝えるのだ
Report on everything that has happened.
But..
しかし…
カリオン様に迷惑はかけられねえ
I can't cause trouble for Lord Carrion.
Tell him I'm resigning my position in the
Beastketeers and leaving the service.
三獣士(さんじゅうし)の地位を返上し 野(や)に下ると
お伝えしてくれ
Thank you for all you've done for me.
今まで仕えてくれて 感謝する
Sir Phobio...
（エンリオ）フォビオ様…
俺は修羅となり
I will become carnage itself and force the
Demon Lord Milim to acknowledge my power.
俺の力を魔王ミリムに
認めさせてやる
Very well.
分かりました
I will report to Lord Carrion.
カリオン様に ご報告いたします
But the extent of Charybdis's
power is unknown.
しかし
カリュブディスの力は未知数
Please be extremely careful.
くれぐれも お気をつけください
Sir Phobio is not a fool.
（エンリオ）
フォビオ様は愚かなお方ではない
本当に
カリュブディスがいるのだとしても
Even if Charybdis really is out there,
I'm sure he can subdue it.
従えることができるはずだ
Now, let us be on our way.
（フットマン）
では 向かうとしましょう
Yeah. If my power and that
of Charybdis can be combined,
俺とカリュブディスの力を
合わせたなら
I bet I can turn Demon Lord Milim's
annoying face into a sobbing mess.
あの魔王ミリムの憎たらしい面を
泣きっ面に変えてやれるだろうぜ
（フットマン）
ホッホッホ！　その意気です
That's the spirit!
Yeah! I'll be cheering you on!
（ティア）
うんうん あたいも応援してるよ！
（ミリム）ぷはあ〜！
（シオン）ぷはっ！
（シュナ）ぷはあ！
What do you think of that?! I won!
どうだ 私の勝ちなのだ
I can stay underwater longer than you two!
私のほうが
長い時間 潜ってられるのだ！
（シオン）
いいえ 勝ったのは私です
No, it was I who won.
No, it was only by a
slight margin, but I won.
（シュナ）違います
ほんの僅かの差ですが
私の勝ちです
負けを認めないとは ずるいぞ
シオン シュナ
No fair refusing to admit
defeat, Shion and Shuna!
よ〜し だったら もう１回だ
決着をつけてやる！
Okay, then, we'll do it again!
Let's settle the score!
いいでしょう　もう一度
Very well. One more time.
本来なら お風呂に潜るのは
良くないことですが
It's really not a good idea to stay
underwater in the bath, but let's do it.
やりましょう
（３人）せ〜の…
Ready... go!
（お湯しぶきが上がる音）
（リムル）ハア…
Seems like they're having fun.
（リムル）
あっち 楽しそうだなあ
向こうに行けばよかったかな
Maybe I should've gone to that side.
Over here is just...
こっちは…
an old dude.
おっさん
Hey, how long do you intend
to stay in this town?
（リムル）
なあ
いつまで この町にいるつもりだよ
Are you still not convinced
that we're harmless?
まだ 俺たちが無害だと
納得してないのか？
Huh? Ah, no...
（フューズ）え？　あ… いえ
リムル殿の疑いは
とっくに晴れているんですがねえ
My suspicion of you is long gone now.
Then why?
（リムル）じゃあ なんでだよ？
Well, this place is just so comfortable.
（フューズ）
いやあ… ここは実に
居心地がよろしくてですな
I haven't had a real break in so long.
ろくに休みもなかったですし
I felt it would be a good
thing to slow down and relax.
ゆっくり羽を伸ばすのも
いいのではないかと
Come on, man...
（リムル）お前なあ…
"I will see for myself whether or not
you are truly an ally of Humans."
“あなたが本当に
人間の味方なのかどうか”
“しっかりと
確かめさせてもらうことにします”
After you sounded so cool saying that...
とか
かっこいいこと言ってたくせに
（フューズ）はあ〜
（リムル）聞いちゃいねえ！
He's not even listening!
Hey!
（リムル）おい！
（フューズ）え？
Eh?
What's going on with Youm
and his guys, anyway?
（リムル）
それに ヨウムたちの件は
どうなってんだよ？
You promised to help make them look
like the champions in our place!
俺たちの代わりに
英雄に仕立て上げる—
協力をしてくれる約束！
Ah...
"Ah" isn't an answer!
（リムル）
“ああ”じゃないって！
もう ヨウムたちは旅立ったんだぞ
Those guys already left, you know!
They went to build a reputation
as champions everywhere.
英雄として各地で名を売るためにな
それなら問題ないですよ
既に仕込みは終わらせております
That won't be a problem.
I've already finished setting things up.
You have?
（リムル）そうなの？
Yes.
I've already laid the groundwork
for spreading the word that they're
ちゃんと オークロードを倒した
英雄として名を広められるように
the champions who defeated the Orc Lord,
根回ししてあります
そして リムル殿たちは
and for spreading the rumor
that you and your people
それを手伝った害のない
魔物たちだと うわさになるように
are the harmless monsters who helped them.
Oh... Well, good, then.
（リムル）そっか… ならいいや
He may be taking it easy,
but I guess he's done his part.
（リムル）
のんびりしてても
やることは やってんだな
Well, I'll be heading back now.
（フューズ）さて 私は お先に
Oh, I almost forgot.
（リムル）ああ そうだ
I'd like to build a road from
here to your Kingdom of Blumund.
お前たちのブルムンド王国へも
道を作ろうかと思ってるんだけど
Eh?
いや… え？　いやいや…
Er... Wha? Oh, well...
I'd certainly appreciate that,
それは ありがたいことですが
大規模な国家事業になりますぞ？
but that would be a national
undertaking on a huge scale.
The budget would be immense.
莫大(ばくだい)な予算が…
Exactly, Fuze-kun!
（リムル）そこだよ フューズ君！
K-Kun?
く… 君(くん)？
リムル殿に
そう呼ばれると
Somehow, hearing you call me
that makes me feel uneasy...
なんだか背中が
むずがゆいのだが…
Don't worry about that, Fuze-kun!
（リムル）
そんなことはいいんだよ
フューズ君
Having a road would make it easier
for us to do business, wouldn't it?
道が出来れば
今後の取り引きにも便利だろ？
Naturally, we'll handle the physical work.
当然だが 作業は
俺たちが引き受けようじゃないか
However...
ただし…
However?
ただし？
I want to sell our specially-made
goods to other countries,
（リムル）
我が国の特産品を
ほかの国にも売りつけたいので
so I'd like you to introduce me to someone
who can give all the advice I need.
もろもろの相談ができる人物の
紹介を頼みたい
Very well. That's a simple matter!
分かりました
お安いご用です
Good, good.
Maybe I should go over there after all...
（リムル）
やっぱり 向こうに行こうかな
ここに？
It's in here?
Yep!
（ティア）そうだよ！
It hasn't been revived yet, but its
thirst for destruction is pouring out.
（フットマン）
まだ復活していませんが
破壊への渇望が漏れ出ています
Such emotions are our
absolute favorite treat.
そうした感情が大好物な
我々だからこそ
That is how we were able to find it.
発見できたのですけどね
You're right... I can feel
something bizarre in the air.
確かに…
異様な妖気を感じるな
Charybdis...
カリュブディス…
Under normal circumstances,
（フットマン）
カリュブディスの復活には
本来 大量の死体が必要です
reviving Charybdis would
require many corpses.
死体？
Corpses?
Charybdis is a type of spiritual lifeform.
（フットマン）
カリュブディスとは
精神生命体の一種です
In order to use its power in this world,
この世界で力を行使するには
肉体を与えてやらねばなりません
one must give it a physical body.
I get it. And?
なるほど　それで？
Your role in all this is...
（フットマン）あなたの役目は…
Wait, are you saying...
まさか お前…
By "subdue," we mean that you
take Charybdis into your body
（フットマン）
従えるとは つまり
カリュブディスを その身に宿し
and unite with it as one being!
ご自身と同一化する
ということなのですよ！
俺の体に…
Into my body?
If you want out, now's your chance!
（ティア）やめるなら 今だよ？
But...
（ティア）でも…
（フォビオ）でも？
But?
This seal might not hold out much longer.
（ティア）
この封印は もう長くもたないかも
もたなかったら どうなる？
And if it doesn't, then what?
It would eventually revive
on its own... I guess?
（ティア）
いずれ自動的に復活しちゃう…
かな？
But it needs corpses, right?
（フォビオ）死体が必要なんだろ？
Yes, but even though it's sealed,
（ティア）そうだけど
封印されてても 自分の復活に
必要な魔物の死体ぐらいは
I'm sure it could acquire the corpses
necessary for revival on its own.
用意できちゃうんじゃないかなあ
And if it does, we might just drop dead!
そうなったら あたいたちは
くたびれ損になっちゃう
Yes, that's right!
（フットマン）そうですねえ
If it revives on its own,
it'll be uncontrollable,
（ティア）
自動復活しちゃったら
制御は無理だろうし
and with an untainted will to destroy,
it won't take orders from anyone.
純粋な破壊の意思だから
誰の命令も聞かないだろうし
So we need to break the seal
before it revives itself
（フォビオ）
復活する前に封印を解き
and take its power for ourselves first?
その力を奪わないとダメ
というわけか？
Huh?
Y-Yeah! Exactly!
そういうこと〜
Very perceptive!
（フットマン）さすがです
いいだろう
Fine.
カリュブディスの力
我が物としてやろう
I'll make the power of Charybdis my own.
I'll do it.
（フォビオ）やってやるぜ
カリュブディスを俺の体に従えて
I'll subdue Charybdis within my own body
and show that impertinent Demon Lord Milim!
あの小生意気な魔王ミリムを…
（フットマン）行きましたねえ
Well, he went in.
He sure did.
（ティア）行ったねえ
He is truly a minion of Carrion's,
with muscles for brains.
（フットマン）
さすがは脳が筋肉で出来ている
カリオンの部下ですねえ
Yeah, that was easy!
（ティア）簡単だったねえ
（フットマン）ホ〜ホッホッホ！
（ティア）ア〜ハッハッハ！
Is this job completed now?
（フットマン）これで終了ですか？
Clayman only told me to revive
Charybdis and send it Milim's way.
（ティア）クレイマンからは
“カリュブディスを復活させて
ミリムに向かわせろ”
としか聞いてないよ
Oh!
The lesser dragon corpse
that I prepared is gone.
（ティア）
用意してたレッサードラゴンの死体
いらなくなっちゃったねえ
But so long as we're prepared,
we've nothing to worry about!
（フットマン）
しかし
備えあれば憂いなしですからね
（フットマン）ホ〜ホッホッホ！
（ティア）アッハッハッハ！
（ギド）ハア… 重かった〜
So heavy...
ワ〜ハッハッハ！
今日も大漁なのだ
Another great haul today!
（リムル）ほう？
Milim's truly amazing!
（エレン）
ミリムちゃんは すごいんですよ
She can locate monsters right
away, so hunting is a breeze!
すぐに魔物を発見するので
今回も狩りが楽々でした
ワッハッハ〜
魔物の発見くらい余裕なのだ
Detecting monsters is a piece of cake!
今夜も ごちそうなのだ
We'll have another feast tonight!
Yep, great work, great work.
（リムル）
うんうん お疲れさん お疲れさん
It was a lot of work, all right.
ホント 疲れやしたねえ
Who's up for a bath and a drink?
（カバル）風呂入って 一杯やるか
I'm up for a drink!
一杯やるのだ
ハ〜ハッハ… あ？
Lady Milim!
（シオン）ミリム様
何者です？
Who's there?!
Whoa, hey!
（リムル）おいおい ちょっと…
（エレン）おっとっと
Gotcha!
（リムル）
この気配は…
This presence...
Treyni-san?
（リムル）
トレイニーさん？
いや… ちょっと違うか
No, she's not quite the same...
I-It's a Dryad!
ド… ドライアドでやす
I've never seen one before...
初めて見た…
I am the Dryad Trya,
（トライア）
私はドライアドのトライア
younger sister of Treyni.
トレイニーの妹です
She has a younger sister?!
（リムル）妹がいたのか！
いや… それより
その殺気と姿は どういう訳だ？
Uh, anyway, what's with that
form and the murderous aura?
There is an emergency.
緊急事態でございます
厄災が近づいています
Calamity is approaching.
Calamity?
（リムル）厄災？
A calamity-class monster,
Charybdis, has been revived.
カラミティモンスターである
カリュブディスが復活いたしました
Charybdis?
（リムル）カリュブディス？
Its violence equals that of a Demon Lord.
（トライア）
魔王に匹敵する暴威であります
My sisters, including Treyni,
have set out to slow its progress,
我が姉 トレイニーたちが
足止めを行っておりますが
but they are no match for it.
まるで歯が立ちません
And it appears Charybdis is heading
そして カリュブディスの目的は
for this land.
この地であるもよう
Huh?!
Against Charybdis, the Ruler of the Skies,
waging war on land is futile.
天空の支配者たる
カリュブディスに対し
地上戦力では無力
I have come to advise you
to bolster your defenses
至急 防衛態勢を固め
and prepare an airborne combat
force as soon as possible.
飛行戦力を用意すべく
進言に参りました
Charybdis was born long, long ago,
（トライア）
カリュブディスは
はるかなる昔に生まれ
死と再生を繰り返しております
and has died and revived many times.
It is a violent Ruler of the Skies.
凶暴なる天空の支配者
No less is expected of the child
さすがは
森の支配者にして守護者たる
of Veldora, the ruler and
guardian of the forest.
暴風竜ヴェルドラ様の申し子と
言えるでしょう
Veldora's child?
（リムル）ヴェルドラの申し子？
Charybdis was generated from a
cloud of Veldora's magicules.
（トライア）
カリュブディスは
ヴェルドラ様から漏れ出た
魔素(まそ)だまりから発生した
魔物なのです
So does that mean Charybdis and
I are sort of like brothers?
（リムル）
じゃあ 俺とカリュブディス
兄弟みたいなもの？
Oh, so is it coming this
way because it's after me?
あ〜 ここを目指してるのは
俺を狙ってるってことか？
Maybe it figured out that
Veldora is inside me...
俺の中に
ヴェルドラが“いる”ことに
気付いているのかも…
If Charybdis has revived, it is a
threat greater than a Demon Lord.
カリュブディスが復活したのなら
魔王以上の脅威となりますよ
Unlike a Demon Lord, this is not
an opponent we can speak with.
何しろ魔王と違い
話が通じる相手ではないのです
You might as well call it a
monster with no intelligence.
（ベスター）
言ってみれば 知恵なき魔物
固有能力のサモン･モンスターで
It's said that it calls shark-like
summon monsters called Megalodons
メガロドンというサメ型の魔物を
異界から召喚して暴れる
from the spirit world to
join it in its rampage.
…と伝えられています
（リムル）
なんだ それ？　オークロードより
やっかいなんじゃ…
What the heck? That sounds
worse than the Orc Lord...
状況は最悪です
The situation could not be worse.
Its summoned Megalodons have occupied
召喚されたメガロドンは
some lesser dragon corpses that were
nearby for some unknown reason.
なぜか 近くにあった
レッサードラゴンの死骸を
依代(よりしろ)にしたもよう
Huh?
They number thirteen.
（トライア）
その数は13
So there's one beast as bad as a Demon Lord,
（リムル）
魔王並みの化け物１体と
召喚された空飛ぶサメが13体…
and thirteen flying sharks that it summoned?
What the hell kind of joke is this?
それは 一体 何の冗談だ？
（シュナ）リムル様
（リムル）ん？
Great Rimuru, what shall we do?
どうなされます？
What do we do? I mean...
（リムル）どうするって…
（ミリム）フッフッフ
（リムル）ん？
何か重要なことを
忘れてはいないか？
Haven't you forgotten something important?
That stupid Charybdis...
カリュブディスごとき…
この私の敵ではない！
is no match for me!
I'll whoop its butt in no time!
軽くひねってやるのだ！
Oh, yeah! That's one way!
（リムル）
おお その手があったか！
そのようなわけにはまいりません
We cannot do that.
This is our town's problem.
私たちの町の問題ですので
Hey, secretary! Don't turn her down for me!
（リムル）
おい 秘書！　勝手に断るな！
えっ だが 私はマブダチ…
Huh? But I'm his besti—
そうですよ
She's right.
It's wrong to rely on you for everything
just because you're a friend.
友達だから何でも頼ろうとするのは
間違いです
リムル様が
どうしても困ったときは
When Great Rimuru is in
desperate need of help,
we would certainly appreciate
your assistance then.
ぜひとも お力添えを
お願い申し上げます
Uh, I'm in pretty desperate need now!
（リムル）
今 めちゃくちゃ困ってるんだけど
They're right, Milim.
（リムル）
そうだぞ ミリム
まあ 俺を信じろ
Just have faith in me.
せっかく せっかく…
And I thought... I'd finally
get my chance to shine...
私の見せ場が
やって来たと思ったのに
Well, it seems like it's after me.
（リムル）
まあ 狙いは俺みたいだし
ミリムに頼り過ぎるのもな…
I can't rely too much on Milim.
Begin preparations to defeat Charybdis!
（リムル）
カリュブディスを倒す
準備しろ！
Yes, sir!
I wanted to show my bestie what I can do...
（ミリム）マブダチのために…
Defeat it?
倒すって…
Are you sure you understand?
あの 分かってるんですか？
You're up against a beast that
even the Dryads couldn't stop.
相手は ドライアドでさえ
足止めできない化け物ですよ
We can count on backup from King Gazel,
since we signed that treaty.
（リムル）
盟約を結んだガゼル王の応援も
期待できるし
We'll just do all we can.
やるだけやってみるさ
逃げないのですか？
You aren't going to run away?
（リムル）
逃げてどうする？
俺が この国でいちばん強い
What good would that do?
I'm the strongest one in this nation.
If it looks like I stand no chance,
I'll run away and think up a new plan,
絶対に勝てそうもないなら
すぐに逃げて 次の策を考えるけど
but otherwise, I should see how strong
it is with my own eyes, right?
そうじゃないなら
正面から自分の目で
敵の強さを確かめるべきだろ？
なるほど 魔物の主(あるじ)…
そうでしたね
I see.
You are the leader of
the monsters, after all.
We're not like Humans who are
done for if they lose their king.
（リムル）
王を失ったら終わりの人間とは
その辺りは違うんだよな
But you know...
（フューズ）しかし あれですな
リムル殿は 我々人間のような
考え方をされるのですね
You think much like we Humans do.
とても魔物とは思えませんよ
It's hard to see you as a monster.
Hmm, maybe...
（リムル）う〜ん そうかもな
It might be hard to believe,
but I actually used to be human.
信じられないかもしれないけど
実は俺 元人間なんだよ
You know about Shizu-san, right?
シズさんのことは知ってるだろ？
I think I'm an Otherworlder,
just like she was.
俺は多分 あの人と同じ
“異世界人”だったんだ
I died in my world...
向こうで死んで…
and was reborn here as a slime.
（リムル）
こっちで スライムに
生まれ変わったんだけどね
シズさん…
Shizu...
Shizu-san entrusted everything to me
as someone from the same homeland.
シズさんは俺と同郷で
あとのことを俺に託して逝ったよ
I gained this form in exchange
for inheriting her will.
シズさんの意思を
受け継ぐ代償として
この姿を得た
I can't go making dumb mistakes
in Shizu-san's form, right?
シズさんの姿で 俺が
かっこ悪いマネはできないだろ？
I see...
そっかあ… やっぱり
リムルさんは信じられる人だよ
So Rimuru really is someone we can trust!
（フューズ）うむ
それに 約束したからな
Besides, I made a promise to her.
A promise?
約束？
シズさんの心を縛る思いを
俺が晴らすってな
That I'd clear away the
feelings that bind her heart.
俺の獲物は魔王レオンだ
My prey is the Demon Lord Leon.
The Demon Lord Leon?!
魔王レオン？
H-He is?!
そ… そうだったの？
You can't call a major figure
like him your "prey"!
そんな大物を獲物とか言っちゃ
マズいでやんす
I mean, compared to the Demon Lord Leon,
そりゃあ 魔王レオンに比べれば
I guess Charybdis would be
easier to handle... maybe?
カリュブディスのほうが
なんぼか楽… か？
Yeah.
そう　魔王レオンは あとだ
The Demon Lord Leon comes later.
Charybdis comes first.
まずは カリュブディス…
Barren Lands
The Western Provinces
The Eastern Plains
Tempest
A battle was about to begin.
（リムル）
戦いが始まろうとしていた
It would take place in between
その場所は
ジュラ･テンペスト連邦国の首都—
the capital of the Jura Tempest Federation,
中央都市リムルと
武装国家ドワルゴンの中間地点
the city of Rimuru,
Canaat Mountains
Great Forest of Jura
Lake Siss
Tempest
Sealed Cave
Kingdom of Falmuth
Kingdom of
Blumund
Armed Nation
of Dwargon
and the Armed Nation of Dwargon.
相手は…
The opponent is...
Charybdis
the calamity-class Charybdis.
厄災
カリュブディスである
Next time, "Charybdis."
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
次回「暴風大妖渦(カリュブディス)」
Charybdis